# **Andres Lopez**

Software Engineer
Email |Github |Linkedin
(470) 918-4104

#### **Summary**

Developing Software Engineer with IT background experience. Transitioning to Front-end development specializing in creating and maining better code base for reusability and finding ways to maximize efficiency. Passionate about learning and development with a desire to apply skills on a professional setting.

## **Experience**

## **IT Support Specialist**

12/2021 - Present

Lovett

- Performed network, software and hardware troubleshooting via in-person or remote and maintaining a solution rate of 95%.
- Created knowledge base articles for escalated complex hardware and software issues.
- Led the rollout of MacOs upgrade project for 300+ machines within 3 months with minimal disruption.
- Conducted training sessions for end-users on new technologies and software applications.

**IT Support 2** 01/2021 - 11/2021

Insight Global

- Provided tier 1 and tier 2 technical support to 300+ employees across multiple locations.
- Managed and monitored ServiceNow/Jira ticket system, ensuring timely resolution.
- Equipment and software deployment . Setting up workstations and deploying software and applications for new and current users using Active Directory, and Jamf.

## **Support Center Analyst**

12/2019 - 12/2020

Rollins

- Supported devices through AirWatch, Intune, and Jamf.
- Offered white-glove technical assistance to executive leadership and end-users.
- Used SCCM for efficient software deployment, which reduced deployment time by 38%.
- Collaborated closely with other IT teams to ensure comprehensive user support.

### Education

Atlanta Technical College: Computer Science

**Year Up:** Year Up is a one-year career development program; the program includes college-level courses, professional training, and a six month internship. • Accrue 800+ hours of hands-on training in IT Help desk, Professional Skills, and Business Communication with specialized training in IT helpdesk.

**Responsive Web Design FreeCodeCamp:** built web pages: HTML (Hypertext Markup Language) for content, and CSS (Cascading Style Sheets) for design.

**C# with Microsoft Developer Certification:** Successfully completed the Foundational C# with Microsoft Developer Certification course. Comprehensive introduction to C# programming, covering its core concepts, syntax, and practical application in software development.

### **Skills & Interests**

Web Development: HTML5, CSS Programming languages: Javascript

Version Control: GitHub

Tools & Software: VS Code, Adobe PhotoShop

Languages: English, Spanish